liferay.com 2016-04-08

# Privacy | Liferay

##  Privacy Policy

This privacy policy applies to ([www.liferay.com](http://www.liferay.com/)) owned and operated by Liferay, Inc. ("Liferay").

Liferay, Inc. and its affiliates ("Liferay") are committed to the privacy of the users of our website. This Privacy Policy was created to inform you of our Personal Information (as defined below) handling practices for the Liferay website ([www.liferay.com](http://www.liferay.com/)). It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. Any Personal Information provided to us will be treated according to the terms of this Privacy Policy. Please note that when you submit information via the website, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of that information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and therefore, we encourage you to read this entire Privacy Policy before submitting any information and/or using the website.

Liferay has received TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this Privacy Policy and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. The TRUSTe program covers only information collected through our website, [www.liferay.com](http://www.liferay.com/) and does not cover information that may be collected through our downloadable software. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily in this Privacy Policy, please contact TRUSTe at https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request.

Liferay complies with the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data, including human resource personal information for employees and other individuals who provide services to Liferay, from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Liferay has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.  To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Liferay's certification, please visit: <http://export.gov/safeharbor>.

##  Collection and use of your Personal Information

"Personal Information" shall mean any information that can be used to identify an individual, and may include, but not limited to, name, email address, postal or other physical address, title, occupation, and other information required to provide a service, deliver a product, or carry out a transaction you have requested.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to Liferay's processing of personal data relating to employees, prospective employees or contract workers. If you are a Liferay employee or contract worker, please refer to the "Employee Privacy Policy" that is available from the HR Department. If you are a prospective Liferay employee or contract worker, please refer to the privacy statement presented at the beginning of the job application process; you will be required to acknowledge that statement before submitting a job application containing personal information to Liferay via its agent, Jobvite.

Some features on the Liferay website are available to users only upon registration. Liferay uses Personal Information in order to allow individuals to access the Liferay community resources such as forums, wiki and the issue tracker.

Liferay also uses identifying information to track web site activity and asset downloads, as well as to target promotional emails based on the provided preferences and to associate forum comments, blog posts and wiki contributions to the specific user.

We will always tell you before we collect any Personal Information and will only use your Personal Information in the way specified when it was collected. Subsequently, we will not change the way your Personal Information is used without your consent.

##  Accessing and updating your Personal Information

In order to ensure that your Personal Information is accurate and up to date, please notify us of any changes to your Personal Information. If you are a registered user, you may update or delete your profile online via the "My Account" area accessed through the "Settings" link in the global navigation or by emailing the Webmaster at [webmaster@liferay.com](mailto:webmaster@liferay.com) or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your request within 30 days.

##  Choice/Opt-Out

You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails or you can contact us at ([portal@liferay.com](mailto:portal@liferay.com)).

You may choose to hide or otherwise withhold displaying certain information on your public profile, including Personal Information, by making changes to your account information on the website.

##  Collection of non-personal/anonymous information

In using our products or services, anonymous network information may be transmitted back to us to determine how users are interacting with our products, assist us with improving our products, and provide alerts regarding available software updates/upgrades. In some instances, Liferay may collect non-personal (aggregate or demographic) data through cookies, web logs, and web beacons. That information is used to improve the usability, performance, and effectiveness of the website. Please read the "Cookies" section below for more information.

##  Sharing your Personal Information

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this Privacy Policy.

We may provide your Personal Information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as shipping your order or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your Personal Information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

We will not share, sell or rent your Personal Information to third parties. We may otherwise disclose your Personal Information when 1) we have your express consent to share the information for a specified purpose; 2) as required by law, such as to comply with subpoenas, court orders or other similar legal process; or 3) we need to protect the personal safety of the users of our website or exercise or defend the legal rights and property of Liferay regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, violations of Liferay's terms of use, or respond to a government request. We may also share or transfer your Personal Information to Liferay's affiliates or to third parties acting on Liferay's behalf strictly for the purposes of processing or storage.

If Liferay is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your Personal Information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your Personal Information.

##  Frames

Some of our pages utilize framing techniques to serve content to from our partners while preserving the look and feel of our site. Please be aware that you are providing your personal information to these third parties and not to [www.liferay.com](http://www.liferay.com/).

##  Facebook Connect and Open ID

You can log in to our website using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain Personal Information with us such as your name (first and last) and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this website to your profile page to share with others within your network.

##  Security of your Personal Information

For our users' security, Liferay utilizes a combination of industry-standard security technologies, procedures, and organizational measures to help protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Liferay Portal, the platform on which our website is built, was benchmarked as among the most secure portal platforms using LogicLibrary's Logiscan suite and uses industry-standard, government-grade encryption technologies including advanced algorithims such as DES, MD5 and RSA. When you enter your personal information we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

Entry into our datacenter is restricted by multiple levels of physical access controls, including key card readers and security systems that limit movement within the facility to authorized areas.

Liferay authorizes access to Personal Information only for those employees who require it to fulfill their job responsibilities. While we strive to protect your Personal Information and follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. We recommend you to take every precaution in protecting your Personal Information when you are on the Internet. If you have any questions about security on our website, you can contact us at [webmaster@liferay.com](mailto:webmaster@liferay.com).

##  Cookies and other Tracking Technologies

Liferay and its third-party service providers utilize technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags and scripts on our website. These technologies are used in delivering targeted Liferay content (not advertisements), analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. For more information about the use of these technologies by our third-party service providers and how they use your information, please refer to the following disclosures:

HubSpot: <http://knowledge.hubspot.com/cookies>  
Google Analytics: <https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage>

##  Local Storage

Liferay uses Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML 5 to collect and store information.

##  Analytics / Log Files

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this [to improve services we offer you, to improve marketing, analytics, or site functionality.

##  Behavioral Targeting / Re-Targeting

We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other websites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and web beacons to collect non-personal information about your activities on this and other websites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [Here](). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising in general. You will continue to receive generic ads.

##  Data retention

Liferay will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services.  We will retain and use your information as necessary to provide you with our website-based services, including our Customer Portal, targeted advertising and website content, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

##  Liferay Community

If you participate or contribute to Liferay's forums, wikis, documentation-related pages, and other pages within the Liferay website ("Community"), the information you provide there (including your first and last name) will be made broadly available to others, potentially inside or outside Liferay, who have access to the Community. Also, please recognize that certain forums may have additional rules and conditions. Each participant's opinion within a forum or chat room is his or her own and does not reflect the opinion of Liferay. To request removal of your Personal Information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [legal@liferay.com](mailto:legal@liferay.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your Personal Information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

Testimonials

We display testimonials of customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. Such testimonials may include personal quotes along with the person's name. If you wish to update or delete a testimonial or your personal quote, you can contact us at pr@liferay.com.

##  Public Profiles

The profile you create on our site will be publically accessible unless otherwise indicated. You may change the privacy settings of your profile through your account portal.

If you believe that an unauthorized profile has been created about you, you can request for it be removed by contacting us at [webmaster@liferay.com](mailto:webmaster@liferay.com)].

##  Linked websites

Our website may provide links to other third-party websites that are outside our control and not covered by this policy. For example we use SourceForge.net for the download of our products and we also provide links to partners and clients on our website. We cannot extend the warranties under this declaration on data protection to such websites. Nor does the fact that we refer to such websites mean that we adopt their contents as our own. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their respective privacy policies. We encourage you to review the privacy policies posted on those and all websites you visit.

##  Social Media Widgets

Our website includes social media features, such as the Facebook Like button. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with these features are governed by the Privacy Policy of the company providing it.

##  Your California Privacy Rights

Residents of the State of California, under a new provision of the California Civil Code, have the right to request from companies conducting business in California a list of all third parties to which the company has disclosed Personal Information during the preceding year for direct marketing purposes. Alternatively, the law provides that if the company has a Privacy Policy that gives either an Opt-out or Opt-in choice for use of your Personal Information by third parties (such as advertisers) for marketing purposes, the company may instead provide you with information on how to exercise your disclosure choice options.

You are a California resident and want to request information on how to exercise your third party disclosure choices, please send a request to [legal@liferay.com](mailto:legal@liferay.com).

##  Children

Our website is not directed to children and we do not knowingly collect any personal information from children under 13 years of age through our sites.

##  Questions or comments?

Should you have any privacy-related questions or comments related to this Privacy Policy, please send an email to [legal@liferay.com](mailto:legal@liferay.com).

##  Policy updates

We may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on our website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at: Liferay, Inc., 1400 Montefino Avenue, Diamond Bar, CA 91765, or [legal@liferay.com](mailto:legal@liferay.com).

Last Updated: March 9, 2015
